怎么了
What's wrong?
爸爸  听说她死了
Dad, they're saying she's dead.
谁死了
Who's dead?
海利·布鲁  高格网上都登了
Hayley Blue. The Gawker web site just posted it.
你喜欢的乐队里的女孩
Oh, the girl from the band you like.
网站上说在切尔西的小巷里发现她的尸体
They say they found her body in an alley in Chelsea.
宝贝  那会不会是谣传
Oh, angel, are you sure it's not just a rumor?
依我看  八卦博客一般都是不实报料
I mean, those gossip blogs, they don't really check facts.
上次那个消息就是真的
They were right when they said
海利打算单飞  离开乐队
Hayley was breaking up the band to go solo.
如果有什么事情
Look, if there was any truth to it,
贝克特警探肯定会打电话
I'm sure Detective Beckett would've called by now.
脖子断了
Broken neck.
初步推断这是致死原因
At least, that's my prelim.
没钱包  没手机  没身份证
No wallet, no phone, no I.D.
不用查了
She doesn't need I.D.
你认识她吗
You know her?
-你确定是她吗  -海利·布鲁
- Are you sure it's her? - That's Hayley Blue.
去年我带阿丽克西斯去看过她的表演  蓝色药丸
I took Alexis to see her band, the blue pill, last year.
出什么事了
What happened?
看着像被人杀害后
Well, it looks like she was killed off-site,
弄到这里再布置好
Then brought here and staged.
死亡时间
Time of death?
差不多是零点到三点之间吧
Uh, I'd say between midnight and 3:00 A.M., give or take.
你们听见了吗
Do you guys hear that?
-什么  -那首歌  不停地播放
- What? - The song--it's playing again.
在循环播放
It's on repeat.
她的歌"过来  小猫咪"  蓝色药丸乐队
"Here, kitty kitty" by the blue pills. It's one of hers.
这是个线索  对吗
Well, that's gotta be a message, right?
好  让犯罪现场调查组来取证
All right, have C.S.U. bag this,
检查尸体  纤维  指纹  全部
Check the body-- fibers, prints, the whole works.
杀手完全可以把尸体丢进垃圾箱
Guy could've tossed the body in a dumpster.
而不用费劲挂在防火梯子上
Instead he hangs her from a fire escape.
应该是在传达某种信息
He is sending a message.
你们回来的真是时候
It's about time you got back.
这里有一位执著的市民
We've got a very persistent citizen
等着要问几个问题
Waiting to ask you some questions.
阿丽克西斯  你在这里做什么呢
Alexis, what are you doing here?
怎么不去上学
How come you're not at school?
一开始是自习课
Oh, I have study hall first period.
-爸爸  这是真的吗  -宝贝  恐怕是
- Dad, is it true? - Uh, yeah, sweetie. I'm afraid so.
发生什么事了  因为毒品吗
What happened, was it the drugs?
看起来不像  为什么
Doesn't look like it. Why?
她吸毒吗
Did she have a drug problem?
过去吸  不过几个月前去戒毒
She used to. She went to rehab a few months ago
当时她朋友发现她呼吸困难
After her friend found her choking on her own--
好  知道吗
Okay. You know, I-- you know what?
看来你的电脑得重设家长监控了
I think it's time we reset the parental controls on your computer.
拜托  是我在你的电脑里装了家长监控
Please, I had to set parental control on your computer.
-记得吗  -说到这个
- Remember? - Speaking of which--
不
No.
街上没有摄像头
Street was negative for cameras.
我们从小巷提取5到11号大小不等鞋印
We got a dozen shoe prints off the alley, size 5 through 11.
在网上核查过她在机动车管理处的记录
Checked her D.M.V. records online,
她两个月前
She moved from the address
从登记的地方搬走
They have listed two months ago
与海利去戒毒的时间吻合
That was about the same time that Hayley went into rehab.
但看这个
But check this out.
我在海利的苹果里找那首歌
I ran a search for that song on Hayley's iPod,
过来  小猫咪
"Here, kitty kitty."
看看找到了什么
Look what popped up.
-音乐录影带  -看看是否眼熟
- A music video? - See if this looks familiar.
发现她时就是这样吗
Is that how you found her?
想起什么了
Does that mean anything to you?
是  这首歌是海利写的
Yeah. Hayley wrote this song
是关于跟踪她的狂热粉丝
About some obsessed fan who was stalking her.
你知道是谁吗
Do yon know who he was?
等等  可能歌曲里面有
Wait. There might be something in the song.
重放一遍
Play it again.
不采取行动  暗中谋划
"Sitting back and plotting."
听起来她觉得他很危险
Sounds like she thought he was dangerous.
听  就是这段
Yeah. Listen, here's the part.
50英尺以内不得接近
"50 feet or less."
她申请了法院制止令
She got a restraining order against him.
好了  查查这人是谁
All rights, run it and get me a name.
至于你...赶紧回学校
And you... will go off to school.
但我刚才帮忙了
But I was just helpful.
是  但如果能帮上忙
Yes, but if I let you out of class
就让你不上课的话  你永远都上不了课
Every time you were helpful, you'd never go.
可我今天没法认真听讲
But I won't be able to focus on school today.
没法集中注意力
I just can't concentrate.
班上其他同学不也没几个
Which would make you just like
注意听讲的嘛
All the other kids in your class.
-爸  -我没开玩笑  否则我就打电话给督学办
- Dad. - I am serious. Or I will call the truant officer.
-还有督学办吗  -预算不足
- Do you still have truant officers? - Budget cuts.
你真走运
Oh, you're so lucky.
找到跟踪者了
Found your stalker.
弗兰可·马库兹  又名弗兰克·马克
Franco Marquez-- a.k.a. Frankie Markie.
海利曾六次对他提出指控
Hayley filed half a dozen complaints against him.
根据记录  他甚至想闯入她的住宅
It says here that he even tried to break into her apartment.
她指控他时  他居然在法庭上
And when she filed against him, he showed up in court
管她叫
And he called her a...
B-i-t-c-h[婊子]
B-i-t-c-h.
她能拼出来  警探
She can spell, detective.
也许比你还强
Probably better than you.
把他带来
Bring him in.
至于你  去上学
And you, to school.
-好  -谢谢
- Fine. - Thank you.
-怎么了  -没什么  只是看惯了
- What? - Nothing. It's just, I'm so used to you
你一直以来表现得像个12岁的小孩
Acting like a 12 year old all of the time.
好久没见你像个父亲了
It's kind of refreshing see you as a father.
这样就喜欢我了吗
Makes you want me, right?
又变回12岁了
And there's the 12 year old again.
你给谁打电话
Who are you calling?
艾利森·金康复中心
Ellison-King rehab center.
明星大腕都在这里戒毒
It's where all the stars go to clean up.
我猜  海利离开时
I figured Hayley must have given them
一定把自己的住址告诉他们了
Her home address on her exit interview.
海利如果要戒毒  就一定选这个中心
If Hayley cleaned up. That's where she would've gone.
布什夫人  康复中心透露
Mrs. Busch, the rehab center said that
你们夫妇支付了治疗费
You and your husband payed for her treatment
离开中心后  她搬去跟你们一起住了
And that she moved in with you after she left the facility.
她和我们就像一家人
Yeah, she'd become like family.
唱片制作人都出钱帮艺人戒毒吗
Do all record producers pay for their artists to go to rehab?
不  多半是给他们毒品  假装没看见
No, most just score them drugs and then look the other way.
经纪人给艺人大麻  好让他们放松
Their manager gets 'em some pot so they can relax.
制作人给艺人毒品好让他们
The producer gets them some blow so they can--
继续开工
So they can work.
有的人给艺人海洛因
Then someone gets 'em heroin.
我们找到海利时  她已经上瘾了
By the time we got to Hayley, she was already hooked.
我们告诉她  如果能戒掉毒品
We told her our door was always open
会永远欢迎她
If she wanted to get clean.
她的水平远上乐队其他人之上
She was always better that band.
她是个天才
She was the talent.
最后当乐队解体后
Well, when they finally broke up,
她想戒毒  所以我们接受了她
She wanted off the drugs, so we took her in.
她做好了准备
She was ready.
她重新灌唱片  却死在歌迷手上
She is recording again. And to be killed by a fan.
其实  我们尚不确定凶手就是弗兰克
Actually, we don't know for sure that it was Franco.
-不确定  -不
- You don't? - No
那是因为你没听到她在半夜三更
You weren't there in the middle of the night
尖叫着惊醒过来
When she was waking up screaming,
害怕同样的事再发生
Terrified that something like this was gonna happen.
我们本想保护她
We were supposed to protect her.
本应该再加把劲把她找回来
We should've tried harder to find her.
找回来
To find her?
上周一  工作室有个研讨会  她没来
Last Monday, she didn't show up at the studio for a session.
我们回家时  她已经走了
When we got home, she was gone,
还带走了衣服  手表和珠宝
So were her clothes, her watch, her jewelry--
值钱的都拿走了  我们猜想
Anything she could sell. We figured--
她的毒瘾又犯了
She had relapsed.
我们给她打电话  但不在服务区
We tried calling her, but her cell phone was disconnected.
你知道  不说一声就走不像她的作风
It, you know, it wasn't like her to just disappear.
她肯定受到什么惊吓
Something spooked her.
海利有亲人吗
Did Hayley have any family?
有一个姐姐叫斯凯
Yeah. A sister. Sky.
你们知道哪里能找到她吗
Do you know where we could find her?
无论在哪里  总是离不开毒品
Wherever she is, she probably has a needle in her arm.
海利从康复中心回来
When Hayley got out of rehab,
总在说要去救斯凯
All she could talk about was saving Sky.
海利的行为  让斯凯不想被救
Not that Sky wanted saving after what Hayley did to her.
海利做什么了
What did Hayley do to her?
她成名了
She got famous.
失陪
Oh, excuse me.
找到狂热歌迷了
Our fanatic fan is rabbiting.
邻居看见他早上背着包
A neighbor saw him leaving with a backpack this morning.
从住处匆匆离开
From the looks of his place, he left in a hurry.
-知道他要去哪里吗  -他要离开此地
- Any idea where he was going? - Yeah. Away.
他今早买了张长途车票
He also charged a bus ticket at port authority this morning.
往北边跑了
He's headed upstate.
汽车五分钟前出发的  听见了吗
Bus pulled out five minutes ago. You hear that?
好  带上  行动
All right, got it. Go.
把手举起来  快点
Hands where I can see 'em, now!
待着别动
Nobody move!
弗兰可·马库兹
Franco Marquez,
你因涉嫌杀害海利·布鲁被捕了
You're under arrest for the murder of Hayley Blue.
起来  快站起来
Get up. Get up here!
轻点儿  你弄疼我了
Easy! Easy, man! god, you're hurting me!
《灵书妙探》
第二季  第七集
你们蠢到家了
You guys are so stupid.
我爱海利  她是我的精神伴侣
I loved Hayley. She was my soul mate.
我为什么要杀她呢
Why would I kill her?!
那你跑什么
Why did you run?
我听说你们怎么找到她的
When I heard how you found her,
就知道你们想些什么
I knew what you'd think.
她写了一首关于我的歌  所以我当然
Oh, she wrote a song about me, so of course I must have k--
昨天午夜之后你在哪里
Where were you after midnight last night?
昨晚最后她唱了一首
She played a set at the bitter end last night...
全新歌曲
Brand-new song.
完全出乎意料
It was, like, a total surprise.
既没有电邮也没有海报的预告
Like, there was no e-mail blast or nothing,
所以我没去
So I wasn't there
我问你当时在哪里  没问你去没去
I asked you where you were, not where you weren't.
有人把音乐会录下会  然后发到网上
Someone recorded the concert and posted it online.
全是病毒
It's gone totally viral already.
所以我当时在家  自己的房间里
So that's where I was-- at home in my room
听海利最后的演出
Listening to Hayley's final show.
最后的演出  你似乎知道这是她的终曲
You say final show like you knew it was gonna be her last.
我知道  海利也知道
I did know. So did Hayley.
她知道自己昨晚会死
She knew last night she was gonna die.
听听看
Listen.
她的新歌
Her new song.
死神越走越近
"Death, she grows near"?
她知道  凶手准备昨晚动手
She knew he was gonna killer last night.
凶手也知道可以把罪名推给我
And he knew he could frame me when he did.
你说的是谁
Who are you talking about?
我知道我本不该  但是
I know I'm not supposed to, but...
有制止令嘛  我还是跟踪了她
The restraining order... I followed her.
我走到街角时听到他冲她大喊大叫
I came around the corner, he was yelling at her.
扬言要宰了她
He said he was gonna kill her.
谁说的
Who said?
弗兰可  你看见谁了
Franco, who did you see?
扎克·麦斯格
Zack Metzger,
她的吉他手
Her guitarist.
扎克·麦斯格吉他偶像  青少年时期记录没拿到
Zack Metzger, guitar god-- juvie records are sealed,
但成年后有过多次前科
But he's got a half a dozen priors as an adult.
有几次是家庭暴力
Couple of 'em are domestic assaults, too.
看来  他喜欢打女人
Apparently, he likes to hit women.
瞧这家伙
Look at this guy.
如果我是个女人  我会反击
If I was a woman, I'd just hit him back.
你觉得他像凶手吗
Does he look like a killer to you?
对我来说所有人都像凶手  卡塞尔
Everybody looks like a killer to me, Castle.
工作需要
Job requirement.
刚刚收到第20分局
Hey. so... I just took a report
接待人员发来的消息
From the receiving officer at the 20th precinct.
他在新闻里认出了海利
He recognized Hayley from the news.
-说什么了  -他说在警局见过海利
- And? - He says Hayley showed up at their door
就在失踪当天  她有份报告要交警局
To file a report the day she went missing.
-什么内容  -他不清楚
- About what?  - He doesn't know.
她要求跟警探说话
She asked to speak with a detective.
等接待人员找到警探的时候
By the time the receiving officer found one,
她却溜走了
She'd skipped out.
主动找警察的唯一理由就是来报案
There's only one reason you go to the cops--to report a crime.
也可能是找警察帮忙  感到自己有危险
Or to get help because you think you're in danger.
海利的事我们都听说了
We heard about what happened to Hayley.
-真糟  不是吗  -要纸巾吗
- Sucks, right?  - Can I get you a tissue?
有人看到你们起过争执
We have a witness who saw you guys fighting.
-那又如何  -她现在死了
- So?  - So she's dead now.
-不是我杀的  -能肯定吗
- Well, I didn't kill her. - Are you sure about that?
就没有情绪过激
You sure you didn't get a little high,
可能跟你的队友发生了点小摩擦
Maybe pull a "hulk smash" on your band mate?
-当然确定  -星期六的0点
- Yeah. yeah, I'm sure. - Where were you
到凌晨3点之间  你在哪里
Between midnight and 3:00 a.m. on Sunday night?
我们有场演出
We had a gig.
在82号剧场为花季16少女们演出
Gillespie Sweet 16 over on 82nd.
演出大概在凌晨一点半结束
We finished around 1:30.
收拾完再出来已经2点了
We packed up and we were out by 2:00.
我和尼克一起打的去威廉斯堡
Me and Nick shared a cab to Williamsburg.
我用信用卡结帐  满意了
I paid with a credit card. Are we done?
给花季少女们办派对
Wow. Sweet 16 parties.
海利在乐队时  你们不是为名流演出吗
When Hayley was with the band, weren't you opening for pink?
你们到底想听什么
What do you guys want me to say?
她玩消失  还要单飞
Okay, she screwed all of us when she had her little meltdown
把我们整个乐队都毁了
And decided to go solo.
恨她吗  恨  宰了她吗  没有
Do I hate her? Des. Did I kill her? No.
为什么起内讧
What'd you guys fight about?
这个自私的婊子
Her being a selfish bitch.
自从她发觉
She found out
她是吸引观众的不可或缺的法宝
That we were holding auditions for her replacement.
就给我们下了最后通牒
And she had those d-bag producers send us
-一封警"号"信  -或者说"警告信"
- A cease and resist letter. - Or a cease and desist letter.
我们乐队以"蓝色药丸"而扬名
We made the reputation for the name "Blue Pill,"
不过所有权在她手上
But she owned it.
所以呢  她就玩消失  跑得无影无踪
So what? She has a meltdown and disappears off the map,
我们连自己乐队的名字都用不了
A-a-and we can't use our own damn name?
-见鬼  现在连被捕都泡汤了  -瞧你这词儿选的
- Hell, we can't even get arrested now. - Poor choice of words.
好
Okay.
海利的姐姐马上到停尸房去认尸
Hayley's sister is on her way to the morgue to identify the body.
别出城
Don't leave town.
但洗澡请随意
But feel free to bathe.
对  请现在就派保安来
Yeah, we need security down here right away.
出什么事了
What's going on in there?
海利·布鲁的姐姐  斯凯
Uh, Hayley Blue's sister Sky
对妹妹的死反应过激
Is having a very emotional reaction to her sister's death.
你这个伪君子  看看谁先挂了
You hypocrite! Who's dead now, huh?
你挂了
You are!
斯凯
Sky.
你来干什么
What do you want?
-我在跟妹妹说话  -我是凯特·贝克特警探
- 'cause I'm talking to my sister. - I'm detective Kate Beckett.
方便的话  需要问你几个问题
I'd like to ask you a few questions, if that's okay.
-你是警察  -对
- You're a cop? - Yeah.
-那是刀吗  -我犯法了吗
- Is that a knife? - Am I breaking the law?
对
Yeah.
严重吗
Bad?
非常严重
Pretty bad.
想听我爆料吗
Do you want to know a secret?
我想大概是我杀了她
I think I might have killed her.
你怎么杀的
How did you kill her?
我让她行行好  去死给世人看
I told her to do the world a favor and drop dead.
然后她照做了
And then she did.
很搞笑  她很少听我的话
It's funny. She usually doesn't listen to me.
为什么叫她去死
Why would you tell her to drop dead?
-她可是你妹妹  -她是个混蛋
- She was your sister. - She was an ass.
-最后一次见她是何时  -周三或周四  没印象了
- When did you see her last? - I don't know Wednesday, Thursday.
-今天是周几  -在哪里见到她的
- What day is it today?  - Where'd you see her?
她发现  我把她送给我
She found me selling a bracelet
当生日礼物的镯子给当了
That she bought me for my birthday.
知道她住哪里吗
Do you know where she was staying?
不  她离开布里和伊恩那之后  就不知道了
No, not since she left Bree and Ian's--
两个成天去教堂的伪信徒
The church of holier-than-thou.
她说要去个远离尘嚣的地方
She said she was going off the grid.
甚至连电话都没有
She didn't even have a phone.
特工义勇先锋  海利·布鲁
Secret agent Clean and Sober-- Hayley Blue.
-为什么离开他们  -她一直在逃离
- Why'd she leave their place?  - She always leaves.
你说过  她上周找过你
You said she was looking for you last week.
对  她有话对我说  很重要的话
Yeah. She had something to tell me, something important.
是什么
What?
我不知道  因为我叫她见鬼去吧
I don't know, 'cause I told her to go screw herself.
我真的不需要她来帮我
I mean, I really don't need her trying to fix me
来试图拯救我  或者对我承诺
Or trying to save me or making promises
一些她根本做不到的事
That she knew she wasn't gonna be able to keep.
她对你承诺什么了
What promises would she make?
她说我还能回归乐队
She said that I could come back.
她说我们还是一个团队
She said that we were gonna be a team.
但我一定得戒毒
But I had to get clean.
你得戒毒  宝贝儿
"You gotta clean up, baby girl.
不然就完蛋了
"You're gonna end up dead."
就这么说风凉话
Hmm. Thus, irony.
为什么就该我戒毒
How was I supposed to get clean...
连她自己都戒不掉
When she couldn't even do it?
等等  她又开始复吸了
Wait a minute. she was using again?
那天我见她之后  她跟托尼在一起
Yeah, she was with Tony the day after I saw her.
托尼是谁
Who's Tony?
我的毒品贩子
My dealer.
她正递给他一叠钱
She was handing him a wad of cash.
我在想  要是她又开始复吸了
I was just thinking, if she was using again,
就能解释  她为何要离开她的经纪人
That would explain why she left her producers,
但不能解释她为何被杀
But not why she was killed,
谁杀了她或为何去报警
Who killed her or why she went to the police.
我刚说的话没这么难懂吧
What I just said was not confusing enough
-看你像听懵了  -帕尔马特刚来电话
- For your face to do what it's doing. - That was Perlmutter.
刚从实验室拿到毒性检测报告
The tox results just got back from the lab.
海利体内未发现毒品痕迹
There were no drugs in Hayley's System.
她一点毒品没沾  神志完全清醒
She was 100% clean and sober.
那他为何会给那个毒品贩子托尼
Then why was she giving a wad of cash
那么一大叠钱
To Tony the drug dealer?
-她不是想买毒品  是想买枪  -买枪
- She didn't want drugs. She wanted a gun. - A gun?
还不要点22口径的枪
Not a punk-ass .22 either.
要点38口径的  她想找人拼命呢
A .38. She wanted to put a hole in a brother.
既然她都死了  我想我那会真做对了
Seeing as she's dead, I say I did the right thing at the time.
-那女的吓坏了  -怕什么
- The girl was scared. - Of what?
她没说  我也没问
Didn't say, and I didn't ask.
她就只想买枪
She just wanted the gun.
-你确定吗  -打算教我怎么当法医
- Are you sure?  - You telling me how to do my job?
不  帕尔马特  我可没这么想
No, Perlmutter. I'm not trying to tell you how to do your job.
很好  该交待的都告诉你
Good, 'cause that's all you get.
我只是...  喂  他甩我电话
I just... hello? He just hung up on me.
他只能跟死人打交道  总归是有原因的嘛
There's a reason he hangs out with dead people.
他说什么了
So what did he say?
他鉴定出  在海利脸上画出笑脸
He identified the lipstick that was used
所用的那支唇膏
To paint a smile on Hayley's face
是丹妮娜·博伦的天鹅绒触感系列唇膏  岩浆红色
As Daniella Bolan's Velvet Kiss Lipstick--Lava red.
那枪呢  他说那枪什么了吗
Yes, but what about the gun? What'd he say about the gun?
还以为你不会问呢
Oh, I thought you'd never ask.
他们在海利手上发现弹药残留
They found gunpowder residue on Hayley's hands.
就是说她不但买了枪  还用了
So not only did she buy a gun, but she used it.
那为什么我们没找到
But why didn't we find it?
因为我们发现的  不是她被害的现场
That's because we didn't find her where she was killed.
有人袭击了她  是她所害怕的那个人
So someone attacked her, someone that she was afraid of.
她想朝他开枪  然后争斗中
She tries to shoot them, and in the struggle,
袭击者扭断了她的脖子  把她拖到小巷里
The assailant breaks her neck, drags her down an alleyway,
倒吊起来  在她脸上画了个笑脸
Hangs her upside down, paints a smile on her face,
摆弄得就像她的音乐录影带里一样
Which apparently was a lot like a music video
这跟我们的凶手没有任何关系
That has nothing to do with our murder.
你这么说的时候
You thought you sounded so smart
-自我感觉非常良好  是吗  -好吧  神秘作家先生
- When you started that sentence,didn't you? - Mr.Mystery Writer Man,
-你的畅销秘诀又是什么  -我会让管家来想
- What's your best-selling theory? - I'm gonna go with the butler.
-管家  -没有灵感的时候  我们都这么干
- The butler?  - That's who we always go with when we run out of ideas.
-阿丽克西斯怎么样  -阿丽克西斯
- How about Alexis? - Oh, Alexis.
她很合适啊  跟这案子没有关系
She's perfect-- she's peripheral to the case,
我们不会怀疑她  她也没有犯罪动机
We don't suspect her, she has no alibi.
好吧  不如这样  你先回家
Okay, I'll tell you what, why don't you go home
盘问一下  等她交待后就打我电话
Question her and if she breaks, call me.
如果你杀了人  你会告诉我的  对吗
If you killed someone, you would tell me, right?
当然
Of course.
得让你帮忙毁尸灭迹的啊
I'd need help hiding the body.
不愧是我女儿
Ah ha ha. That's my girl.
-亲爱的  -收到我发的消息了吗
- Hi, darling. - Did you get my texts?
对  你真的见到了"蓝色药丸"的其他成员
Yeah. Did you really meet the rest of the blue pill?
是的  我只能说  距离产生美
Yes, I did, and all I can say is, admire them from afar.
-你在听什么  -海利最后一场演出
- What are you listening to? - It's Hayley's last performance.
她听了一晚上  没完没了
Oy! She hasn't stopped listening to it all night.
这场演出叫"门槛"
It's called "Threshold."
是吗  听起来不错
Oh, yeah. It's, uh, it's pretty.
虽然有点怪
A little creepy, though.
-非常怪  -怎么会怪呢
- Very creepy. - How's it creepy?
"死神越走越近"  简直就像《死神来了》
"Death, she grows near"? It's kinda like "Final Destination,"
但在歌里  她说的死亡  并不真是死亡
But in song form. she doesn't mean "death" death.
那还能是哪种死亡
Well, what other kinds of death are there?
寓意的  隐喻的  象征意义的  精神上的
Allegorical, metaphoric, symbolic, spiritual,
-感情上的  两性间的  -好了好了  够了
- Emotional, sexual-- - Ah, o-okay, okay. That's quite enough.
看来她学的知识过多了
I think I'm paying far too much for her education.
我觉得这是有象征意义的  海利运用了各种
I think this one's symbolic. Hayley was into all sorts
新新人类的意象  命理学  占星术  塔罗牌
Of new age-y imagery--uh, numerology, astrology, tarot.
在塔罗牌里  死神卡并不象征着死亡
And in tarot, the death card doesn't symbolize dying.
而是象征着转变  变化
It symbolizes transformation, change.
听这个
Listen.
我们手中的牌  就好像她正在看牌
"The hands we're dealt," like she's having her cards read.
死神越走越近  意味着变化就要来临
"Death grows near" means change is coming.
这让我想起跟莉莎·奥森在一起
Oh, oh, that reminds me of sitting around with Lisa Olsen
想要解读甲壳虫的歌词
Trying to decode the Beatles' lyrics--
还倒带回去  去确认
Spinning the record backwards and to see if, uh,
保罗是不是死了
Paul was dead.
简直就能忘了时间飞逝
And who could forget the countless hours
我研究过范·海伦乐队《谁上我的床》的歌词
I spent pondering the lyrics to Van Halen's "Hot For Teacher"?
就像在演一出戏
Sounds like a drama is afoot.
谁亲了谁  又是在哪个露天看台
Who kissed whom at which bleachers?
这是"蓝色药丸"的官方网站
No, it's the official Blue Pill web site.
有一个新帖
There's a new thread
-在讨论乐队要重新组合起来了  -什么
- Talking about the band getting back together. - What?
看这个
Look at this.
斯凯·布鲁将取代海利  成为乐队主唱
"Sky Blue is supposed to take Hayley's place as lead singer.
这事已经谈成了
"This is all but a done deal.
听说他们马上开始彩排了
"I heard they're starting rehearsals right away.
-我的天  我的天  我的天  -看这个
- O.M.G.! O.M.G.! O.M.G.! " - And look at this one.
来自约翰·麦克尼金斯经纪公司的消息称
"A source at John Mcginnis Management
此事已经得到证实
"Confirmed it when I called--
"蓝色药丸"确定再聚首
The Blue Pill is definitely getting back together."
纪念海利·布鲁巡回演出
"The Hayley Blue tribute tour.
我以为你说过海利不会让乐队
" I thought you said Hayley wouldn't let the band
-要回这个名字  -她是不会
- Have the name back. - She wouldn't.
-那这怎么说  -海利死了  斯凯是她唯一的亲人
- Then how can they use it? - Hayley is dead and Sky's her only family.
如果这名字原本归海利  那么现在归斯凯了
If Hayley owned the name, then it would go to Sky.
你不会认为斯凯杀了自己妹妹吧
You don't think Sky killed her own sister?
斯凯只有100磅  还是瘾君子
Sky is 100 pounds dripping wet.
她唯一能折断的  是她自己的脖子
The only neck she could break is her own.
约翰·麦克尼金斯经纪公司经济公司  谁是约翰·麦克尼金斯
"John Mcginnis Management." Who's John Mcginnis?
海利原来的经纪人  她戒毒之后就炒了他
Hayley's old manager. She fired him when she got clean.
她没直说他的名字
She didn't say his name,
在她上个月的唱片采访中
But in her interview in "Spin" last month,
她差不多暗指了  他就是那个
She pretty much implied that he's the one
引她吸毒成瘾的那人
That got her hooked to begin with.
如果乐队真的再聚首  他获利最丰
If the band got back together, he'd have the most to gain.
在你看来  这人像凶手吗
Now does that man look like a killer to you?
在我眼里每个人都像凶手
Everybody looks like a killer to me.
工作需要
It's a job requirement.
你就没这么说过斯凯
You didn't say that about Sky.
让我先陶醉一会
Just... let me have this moment.
我跟你们说过了
I told you--
周六晚上  我正在费城观察一支乐队
Sunday night, I was in Philly scouting a band.
投宿在汽车旅馆  看了付费节目
I hit a motel, I watched a little pay-per-view,
然后就睡了
And I went to bed,
这可能说明我的生活品味不高
Which may say something about my taste,
但不能证明我就是个罪犯
But it does not make me a criminal.
但你的犯罪记录可以
But your rap sheet does.
六项轻罪
Six counts of misdemeanor possession,
两项重罪  可能还会增加
Two counts of felony possession with the intent to distribute.
你干了些什么  麦克尼金斯
What'd you do, Mcginnis,
给他们些甜头
Give 'em a little taste,
让他们需要你  依靠你
Make 'em need you, make 'em depend on you?
想知道我做了什么
You want to know what I do?
是我成就了她
I make things happen
当我遇到海利和她姐姐的时候
When I met Hayley and her sister,
她们还在东村的露天咖啡屋驻唱
They were playing open mikes at coffeehouses in the east village.
谁给她找的声乐教练
Who do you think got her a vocal coach?
谁给她请造型师
Who paid for her stylist?
我把一个三流  三流的麦莉·塞勒斯
I took a third-rate-- a third-rate--Miley Cyrus
变成了下一个格温·史蒂芬妮
And turned her into the next Gwen Stefani,
而当我要大赚一票的时候  她却离开了
And right before my payoff, she walks away.
我...
I... I...
但乐队仍旧属于她
And since she owned the band name,
你束手无策
Your hands were tied.
现在她死了
But now that she's dead,
现在你只需要找到斯凯来代替她
All you needed to do was rope in Sky.
听着
Look...
我的看法是
The way I see it,
乐队重组的话  每个人都能赚一大笔
The band gets back together, everybody makes a lot of money,
大家都高兴
Everybody's happy.
除了海利  因为她已经死了
Except for Hayley, because she's dead.
当乐队重新进行巡演的时候
Which will no doubt help us sell lots of tickets
这也能帮我们卖很多票
When the band goes back on tour.
这就是你杀她的原因吗
Is that why you killed her?
我知道自己的权利  我不想再说了
Now I know my rights here, and I'm done talking.
你认为自己有证据  那就逮捕我啊
You think you got a case? Arrest me.
我巴不得能提高点曝光率
I would love to have that kind of publicity.
我从来没像刚才那样深刻体会到
I never fully appreciated the nuances of the word "skeevy"
"Skeevy"的含义
Until just now.
嘿  莱恩  你找到麦克尼金斯
Hey, Ryan, did you get the phone records
以及他经济公司的电话记录了吗
For John Mcginnis and Mcginnis Management?
嗯  弄到了
Yeah, just got 'em.
难道你真认为是他干的
You don't think he did it?
他向我挑衅  以为我不敢抓他
He challenged me to arrest him.
也许他很顽固
He's probably screwed
其实就会唬人而已
And figures bluffing is his best bet.
莱恩  比照一下通话记录和疑犯名单
Ryan, let's cross-reference his calls with our hit list,
看看他是否有和
Find out if he was in contact with anyone
海利比较亲近的人联系
From Hayley's inner circle.
可他当时在费城
What about him being in Philadelphia?
只要找到方法  你甚至能用电话杀人
With the right connections, you can kill with a phone call.
有  这里
Yeah, right here.
在海利死前一天  麦克尼金斯给
Looks like the day before Hayley died, Mcginnis put in
吉他手扎克打了长达十分钟的电话
A 10-minute phone call to Zack, the guitarist.
他有好几个月不参与乐队演出了
He hasn't represented the band in months.
他为什么要在海利死之前给扎克打电话呢
Why would he call Zack the day before Hayley died?
去查查就知道了
Let's go find out.
怎么回事儿啊  你这神经病
What is your problem, you freak?!
你真是疯了
You are completely mental!
你以为你是谁啊  你这个窝囊废
Who the hell do you think you are, loser?!
你给我站住  我在和你说话呢
Don't you walk away from me. I'm talking to you!
你给我走开  再碰我试试
Get the hell away from me! You touch me again,
我发誓  我要杀了你
And I swear to god, I will kill you!
嘿  嘿
Hey! Hey!
去你妈的  你这个蠢女人
Screw you, you stupid whore!
坐下  扎克
Sit down, zack!
哦  闭嘴
Oh, stop!
嘿  斯凯  好了没事儿了
Hey, Sky. it's okay. Sky.
放开我  不要管我
No, don't! leave me alone.
你对她做了些什么
What did you do to her?
我什么都没做  是她攻击我
Nothing, man! She attacked me.
我们在排海利的一首歌
We were riffing on one of Hayley's songs.
前一秒她还在唱歌  下一秒
One minute she's singing along, the next minute,
就开始发疯了  说我是在抄袭海利
She goes postal, starts telling me I'm stealing from Hayley.
她疯了
She's crazy.
现在情况对你很不利  扎克
It doesn't look good, Zack.
把一个打的鼻青脸肿  又杀了另一个
Beating up one blue, killing another?
听着  我已经说过了
Look, I already told you gu--
给我坐下  坐下
Sit down! sit!
现在解释
Now talk.
我已经告诉你们了  我没有杀海利
I already told you guys, I didn't kill Hayley. okay?
我在生日演唱会上  忘了吗
I was at the birthday gig, remember?
是的  在Gillespies' Sweet16号
Right. The Gillespies' Sweet 16?
你中间离开了一个半小时
You took three half-hour breaks in between sets,
在这期间没人看到过你
During which no one remembers seeing you.
你可以轻松溜走然后杀了海利
You could've easily slipped away and killed Hayley.
没人看到我  因为我不想
Nobody saw me because I didn't want to spark up a pipe
在一群青少年中引起混乱
In front of a bunch of teenagers.
你的细心周到还真是令人敬佩
Well, your innate sense of decency is inspiring.
你为什么在海利死的前一天
Why did you talk to John Mcginnis
和约翰·麦金尼斯通话
The day before Hayley was killed?
他是我的经纪人  那也算犯罪吗
He's my manager. Is that a crime?
是前经纪人  在海利解散了乐队之后
Ex-manager. He let all of you guys go
他也让你们都离开了
After Hayley disbanded the group.
他为什么还给你打电话  扎克
So why did he call you, Zack?
我来告诉你  你们都想摆脱海利
I'll tell you why. You both needed to get rid of Hayley
从而夺回乐队
To get the band name back,
他给你打电话  告诉你计划
And he called with a plan.
好吧  没错  他是有个计划
Okay, look, fine, he had a plan.
但不是杀了海利  他想找到斯凯
But it wasn't to kill Hayley. He wanted to find Sky.
为什么
Why?
他听说斯凯和海利又开始来往了
He heard that Sky and Hayley were talking again.
他想我去贿赂她
He wanted me to grease her wheels a bit.
什么  用你的无穷魅力吗
Oh, what, with your vast array of charms?
麦克尼金斯让我给她毒品
Mcginnis wanted me to give her dope
让她去和海利谈谈
And have her talk to Hayley
然后拿回乐队名所有权
And get the band name back.
他知道只有通过斯凯才能接近海莉
He knew that the only way to get to Hayley was through Sky.
所以我就让她吸毒
So I got her wasted, okay?
吸得有点太多了
A little too wasted.
我就自己去找了海利
And I went to go see Hayley myself.
你在海利被杀的那晚见到过她
You saw Hayley the night that she was killed?
你之前应该告诉我们的  扎克
You should've told us that, Zack.
干嘛  让自己嫌疑更大吗
What, make me look even more guilty to you guys?
我才没那么傻  我看电视的
No. I watch TV.
我知道陪审团是怎么做事的
I know how the jury works.
这些小蛛丝马迹就会让你被定罪
These little things get you convicted
对警察说谎也会
So does lying to cops
说下去  说完
Keep going. Spill it.
她在一个咖啡屋
She was at a coffeehouse.
她又开始写歌
She was writing songs again.
之前都好好的直到她电话响了
E-everything was fine until her phone rang.
发生了什么
What happened?
她吓坏了
She freaked.
她按了"忽略"
She hit "ignore,"
但每次她挂断之后  电话又响
But every time she did, it just rang again.
电话每响一次  她变得更害怕
And every time it rang, she just flipped out even more.
你知道那是谁吗
You have any idea who it was?
知道  他们打了很多次
Yeah, because they called so many times,
我看到了来电显示
I saw the caller I.D.
我看到之后也吓了一跳
It scared me when I saw it, too.
上面显示是死神来电
It said it was Death calling.
我以为她没有电话
I thought she didn't have a phone?
她也许不想留下任何痕迹  用付费电话
She probably had a pay-as-you-go plan, paid cash,
然后给电话公司留下错误的信息
And gave the phone company false information.
如果她想避开死神  并如斯凯所说避开
Well, that makes sense if she was hiding from death
通信网络的话  这样做就讲得通了
And trying to stay off the grid like Sky said.
那么  很明显
Okay, so obviously,
电话是人打来的
There's a human being at the other end of the phone.
而那个不知名的人跟踪了她
And whoever it is probably tracked her down
然后杀了她
And then killed her.
那么谁会比较有可能
So who had the dubious distinction
会被海利称为"死神"
Of being known by Hayley as "death"?
好  那首歌是怎么唱的
Okay. well, how does the song go?
"死神  她就在附近"
"Death, she grows near."
"她“  死神是个女人
"she"--death is a woman.
明白你的意思
Okay, following you so far.
阿丽克西斯说海利
Okay, Alexis says that Hayley
喜欢在她的歌里应用塔罗牌里的话
Liked to draw from tarot cards in her writing.
在塔罗牌里  死神并不代表死亡
And in tarot cards, Death isn't death.
死神表示改变
Deah means change.
那么她并不是在躲避死神
Okay, so she wasn't hiding from Death.
她在逃避改变
She was hiding from change.
她讨厌奥巴马
She hated Obama.
谁是改变的化身呢
Who was the embodiment of change?
什么样的女人代表了
What woman represented
海利生活中最大的改变呢
the bigest change in Hayley's life?
送她去戒毒的人
The one who sent her to rehab.
挽救了她人生的人
The one who saved her life.
布雷·布什
Bree Busch?
为什么她的制作人要害她
Why would Hayley's producer want to hurt her?
我不知道  但值得查一下
I don't know, but it's worth a shot.
是你在哭吗
Are you crying?
我在唱她的歌
I was singing her words.
我能听到她的声音
I could hear her voice.
我能感觉到她  就像她在这里
I could feel her, like she was here.
那是因为你妹妹很坚强
That's because your sister was strong.
你以为她又开始吸毒
You thought that she was using again.
但其实她没有  她已经戒掉了
But she wasn't. She was clean.
希望我们能做点什么
I wish there was something we could do.
我们不能把她送到戒毒所或做点别的吗
Can't we send her to rehab or something?
在她自己准备戒掉前  没人能帮她
No one can help her until she's ready to get clean.
我弄到了对布雷·布什的调查执行令
So I called in the warrants you wanted on Bree Busch.
要一天时间才能拿到她的电话记录
Phone records are gonna take a day,
但信用卡记录显示  10点48分她买过东西
But her credit card puts her in the city at 10:48.
刚才我查看了一下谈话记录
Now I checked our interview notes.
她说10点她在布鲁克林的家里
She said she was at home in Brooklyn at 10:00.
那么10点48分她又在哪里
Where was she at 10:48?
在12大道和19大道之间的一个药店
At a pharmacy at 12th and 19th.
-那儿离犯罪现场有三个街区  -是的
- That's three blocks from the crime scene.  - Yeah.
我在想她到底买了些什么
Made me wonder what she was shopping for,
然后我给那药店打了电话
So I called the store.
他们传真过来一张收据
They faxed over a receipt.
一瓶水  巧克力
Bottle of water, energy bar...
和达妮埃拉·博兰熔岩热吻红色天鹅绒唇膏
And a tube of Daniella Bolan velvet kiss lava red lipstick.
和海利脸上的那款唇膏是一样的
That's the same lipstick used to paint a smile on Hayley's face.
好吧  是这样的
Okay, it's true.
她死的那晚我见过她
I saw her the night she died.
之前你为什么不告诉我们这点
Why didn't you tell us that before?
那天她给工作室打来电话
She had called the studio earlier that day.
是我的助手凯利接的电话
She spoke to my assistant Kelly, okay?
她说她要过来拿点东西
She said she wanted to come by and pick up some stuff
她把吉他和一些设备忘这儿了
She'd left behind-- a guitar and some pedals.
那样你就得到了她的新号码
That's how you got her new number.
我马上给她回了电话
I called her back immediately.
你知道  我一直给她打
You know, I kept calling.
她不接
She wouldn't pick up.
我给她发了无数条短信
I must have left half a dozen messages.
最后  我给她留了条信息说
So finally I-I, you know, left her a message saying,
"今晚过来  老地方"
"Come by tonight, you know."
"有人会把你的东西给你"
"Someone will be here to give you your stuff."
但我没告诉她是我  于是她就来了
And I didn't tell her it was gonna be me, so she showed.
那是几点钟
What time was that?
哦  大概11点
Oh, about 11:00.
我说  "除非你告诉我到底怎么回事"
Anyway, I-I said, "I'm not gonna give you your stuff
"否则我不会把东西给你"
"Unless you tell me what's going on,"
你知道吗
You know?
她甚至看都不看我  你得明白
She wouldn't even look at me. You have to understand, um,
我投了那么多钱到这张唱片里面
I had put so much money into this record,
如果她不完成的话  我就要失去工作室
If she didn't finish it, I was gonna lose the studio.
我得让她留下来  懂吗
So I had to get her to stay, right?
反正她也在吸毒
Mm. uh, she was using anyway.
是你给了她毒品
You offered her drugs.
一袋  我给了她一袋
A bag. I offered her a bag.
我说"还有更多"
I said, "there's plenty more where that came from."
我本该
Well, I-I would've, uh...
在她戒毒之后帮助她的
Gotten her help after she finished.
但我不想让她离开
I couldn't let her walk away.
但问题就在这  布什太太
Yeah. well, here's the thing, Mrs. Busch--
海利死时是清白的  她没在吸毒
Hayley was clean when she died. she wasn't using.
后来我才知道
Well, I know that now.
当时  她解开上衣
I mean, she-- she opened up her jacket
给我看了里面藏着的东西  是一把枪
And showed me what was tucked inside--a gun.
她有一把枪
I mean, she had a gun.
她说"我宁愿自杀"
And she said, "I would rather put a bullet in my brain
"也不要再吸毒"
"Than to be using again."
让我重述一下整个过程
Let me make sure I'm getting this right.
你假装为她好  想诱惑她
You lured Hayley here under false pretenses,
而给她毒品  但却引起激烈争吵
Offered her drugs, got into a heated argument,
你想说她是活着走出去的吗
And you're telling me that she walked out of that door alive?
你什么时候换的这隔板上的镜板
When did you replace the panel on this baffle?
我不记得有换过
I-I don't think it's ever been replaced.
有换过  这块比其他的要新一些
Yeah, it has. It's newer than the other ones.
你能小心一点吗
Could you be careful, please?
那些设备很贵的
That's expensive equipment.
卡塞尔  你在干什么
Castle, what are you doing?
很明显  我在这里找到了一个弹孔
Apparently, I'm uncovering a bullet hole.
从洞孔直径来看  是一把点38口径的枪
Judging from the diameter of the hole, it's a .38.
海利手上还有开枪后的痕迹
That gunpowder residue on Hayley's hands?
这就是开枪的地点
This is where the gun was fired.
我不知道那儿怎么会有弹孔
I have no idea how that bullet hole got there.
你和海利争吵
You and Hayley fought.
你知道如果她走了
You knew that if she walked out that door,
你就再也找不到她了
You would never see her again.
所以你从后面抓住了她
And so you grabbed her from behind.
她拿出了枪  你吓坏了
She pulled out a gun. It scared you.
你抓得更紧了  她开了一枪
You held her tight. A shot went off.
你依旧紧紧抓着她
You held her tighter still,
你不明白发生了什么
And before you even knew what happened,
她就停止了挣扎
She stopped struggling.
而你没意识到已经扭断了她的脖子
You broke her neck without realizing it.
不是这样的
That's not what happened.
事实根本不是这样的
That's not what happened at all.
如果这是个意外  是自卫不当的话
If it was an accident, if it was an act of self-defense,
你只要告诉我们事实
You're gonna make this all easier on yourself
事情就简单得多
Just by telling us the truth.
她如果认罪将会被判5年
She's gonna do 20 years
不认就是20年
Instead of pleading out and doing five.
因为内心愧疚还是律师差劲吗
Guilty conscience or lousy lawyer?
求你了布雷  我不能让你蹲20年
Bree, please. I can't lose you for 20 years.
我不能说谎  我没有害死她
I can't lie. I didn't hurt her!
事实不是这样的
That's not what happened.
看来要靠律师了
I guess it's up to the lawyer now
回家告诉阿丽克西斯这个消息
You goin' home to tell Alexis the news?
只是想出去走走
Just thought I'd go for a walk.
有哪里特别想去的吗
Anyplace in particular?
一想到她孤伶伶的我就很难受
It kills me thinking about her out there alone.
走吧  我来开车
Come on. I'll drive.
斯凯
Sky?
你确定扎克说她藏在这吗
Are you sure Zack said she was crashing here?
当然
Yeah.
在那边
It's over there.
斯凯  斯凯
Sky. Sky.
你还好吗
You okay?
能听见我说话吗
Can you hear me?
你吸了多少
How much did you take?
麦克尼金斯给了我们应得的奖励
Mcginnis gave us a signing bonus.
他告诉了我们能便宜买到货的地方
He told us a place we could fix for cheap.
可我没办法去
Mm. I couldn't do it.
海利不希望我这么做
No, Hayley didn't want me to.
我现在清白了
I c... I'm clean.
她会帮我的  对吗
She's gonna help me, right?
不论她在哪
Wherever she is...
她都会帮我的  对吗
She's looking out for me, right?
她已经这么做了
She's already doing it.
来  我们带你离开这
Come on. Let's get you out of here.
斯凯会没事的  对吗
Is Sky going to be okay?
我认为她会的
I think so.
最难熬的时期过去了
The worst part is over.
现在她只需要过好剩下的日子
Now she just has to figure out the rest of her life.
海利呢
And Hayley?
整件事难道只是个愚蠢的意外
The whole thing was just some stupid accident?
太没意义了
It's just so pointless.
我知道
I know.
当我们失去一个喜欢的歌手时
Sometimes when we lose an artist we like,
就好比失去一个好朋友一样
It's kinda like losing a friend.
我记得约翰·列侬死的时候
You know, I remember when John Lennon died...
我躲在房间里一周没出来
I didn't leave my room for a week.
她只有25岁
She was only 25.
我无法想象她没办法再写歌了
I can't help but think about all the songs she won't write
我们也听不到她的歌声了
That we won't get to hear now.
只因为制作人认为她又吸毒了
And all because a producer thought she was back on drugs...
她怎么会那样想
Why would she even think that?
当我们关心的人
You know, when people we care about
突然背叛我们的时候
Suddenly turn against us,
我们会找各种理由去掩饰
We can come up with all sorts of reasons to explain it.
但谁知道真相是怎么回事呢
Who knows what really happened?
我说完了  你还不睡吗
Well, that's it for me. You stayin' up?
可以吗  我只是想再多听一会
Is it okay? i just want to listen a little longer.
当然可以
Of course.
请你倾听  我解释给你听
"I can explain if you're listening."
怎么了  爸爸
What, dad?
这首歌是她死前一周写的
She wrote that song a week before she died,
在她离开制作人去找警察之后
After she left her producers and went to the cops.
可能她想告诉我们发生了什么
Maybe she's trying to tell us what was going on.
被锁沉默里  活生生的地狱中
"Locked up in silence, a living hell."
戒毒所
Rehab?
或者制作人家里
Or her producers.
曾拯救我的  挚爱的你
"The loving hand that saved me."
她的制作人  布雷和伊恩  等等
Her producers Bree and Ian? Wait.
她歌词里说"它的"黑暗还是"他的"
What is she saying there, "its darkness" or "his darkness"?
你越过了我的底线  你怎么能这样
"You stepped across my threshold. How could you?"
天哪  爸爸
Oh, god, dad.
这和我想的是一个意思吗
Does that mean what I think it means?
意思就是  我们抓错凶手了
It means... We have the wrong killer.
凶手的身份在歌词里面
The identity of our killer is in the song?
没错  你听
It's right there. Listen.
我知道  我听过
I know. I already heard it.
你认为如果海利知道谁想杀她
Don't you think that if Hayley knew who was gonna kill her,
她肯定会阻止这次谋杀的
She would've tried to prevent the murder?
现在为止每件事都不符合逻辑
It never make sense up to now.
要是真的一切顺利
Why would she have to disappear
她又何必要躲起来呢
When everything seemed to be going so well?
就在歌词里  她唱出来了
It's in the words. She even says it.
请你倾听  我给你解释
"I can explain if you're listening."
就这样放我走了吗
Just like that, I'm free to go?
你可以走了
Just like that.
你需要填些释放文件表格
You need to sign a few release forms,
如果你不介意的话
If you don't mind.
非常感谢
Thank you so much.
你们找到真正的凶手了吗
Does this mean you found the real killer?
我们马上去逮捕凶手
We're about to make arrest,
太好了
That's great.
你知道更奇妙的是
You know what's even better is it
是海利告诉我们谁是凶手
was Hayley herself who led us to her killer.
她怎么做到的
How'd she do that?
她最后一首歌
Her last song.
她被害那晚唱的那首
The one that was playing the night she died.
网上已经传开了  你们应该知道
It's all over the web. You know the one.
歌词提醒了我
It's the lyrics that really get me.
里面有许多隐含意思
There's so many layers.
听了很久我才明白
It took me a few listens to get to the bottom of them.
开始听的时候
Mm-hmm. first time I heard it,
我以为是关于戒毒所
I thought it was about going into rehab.
确实是这样  走出黑暗的深渊
But it is. It's about coming from a dark place
重新勇敢面对生活
And having the courage to get on with your life.
不同的黑暗  听
Different dark place. Listen.
这段里提到了
This is the part that gives it away.
你越过了我的底线  你怎么能这样
"You stepped across my threshold. How could you?"
我不明白
I don't understand.
有人超越了她的底线  她不愿意这样
Somebody crossed over her threshold. She didn't want him to.
有人威逼她做某些事
Someone forced himself on her.
你们根据歌词推断出这么多东西
You're getting all that from a song?
还有另外一些地方很明显
Well, there's other places where it's more overt.
但如果你听这些歌词
But if you listen to the words,
仔细分析  就能明白
Analyze them, it's all there.
父亲一样的形象  背叛
Father figure, betrayal...
性侵犯
Violation.
实在太可怕了
It's truly awful.
为什么她什么都没说
Why didn't she say anything?
伊恩  她和你说过什么吗
Ian, did she ever say anything to you?
没有  她没有过
No. no, she didn't.
你把海利被害那晚  和她争吵的事
You told your husband about arguing with Hayley
告诉了你丈夫  对吗
The night she was killed, didn't you?
没错  我从工作室回家时  他正好在家
Yes. He was there when I got home from the studio.
我把整件事都告诉了他
I told him the whole thing.
我当时很烦躁 吃了安眠药就睡了
Uh, I was so upset, I took a sleeping pill to get some rest.
就是那时你拿了她的手机
That's when you borrowed your wife's cell phone
还有她的新口红
And her brand-new lipstick.
很巧的是  我们查到了
It's a good thing we'd subpoenaed
你夫人的通话记录
Your wife's phone records
同时  我还神奇地联想到歌词的内容
When I had this whole crazy lyric idea.
否则  我们就不知道
Otherwise, we might have missed out
你给海利发的那些短信息了
On those texts you sent Hayley.
什么短消息
What texts?
短信是11:52从你的手机发送的
Text from your phone at 11:52
伊恩都告诉我了  我得和你谈谈
"Ian told me the whole thing. We have to talk right away."
工作室见
"Meet me at the studio."
我从没发过这个
I never sent that text.
11:54  很抱歉他对你做的一切
11:54 "I'm so sorry for what he did to you."
我要离开他  请来和我谈谈
"I'm leaving him. Please come talk to me."
最后11:56  来自海利的回复
And finally at 11:56, a reply from hayley.
工作室见
"See you there."
你干了什么
What did you do?
挚爱的你  将我逼入绝境
"The loving hand that saved me held too tight."
他假装是你
He pretended to be you
因为就是他威逼海利
Because he was the one who forced himself on Hayley.
他怕她把真相说出来
He was afraid she was gonna talk,
所以装成你
So he pretended.
当海利意识到
By the time Hayley realized
是伊恩在办公室等她时
It was Ian waiting for her at the office,
已经太迟了
It was too late.
伊恩
Ian?
Ian?!
我没有威逼海利
I didn't force myself on Hayley.
是她勾引的我  从她来的那天开始
She seduced me, from the time she moved in
对我说话的口气   触摸我的方式
The way she talked to me, the way she touched me.
现在我们为她做了一切
And now after all we'd done for her,
她却编造谎言来摧毁我们的婚姻
She was gonna make up this lie to destroy our marriage
毁坏我们的事业
And ruin our our business?
-不可能  -所以你拧断了她的脖子
- No. - So you snapped her neck.
她的枪没起任何作用  对吗
The gun didn't do her any good, did it?
你比她强壮多了
You were too strong,
就像你侵犯她的那晚一样
Just like the night when you assaulted her.
是你杀了她
You killed her.
你差点就逃脱了
And you almost gonna away with it.
但海利还是开了口  不是吗
But Hayley wouldn't shut up, would she?
你很狡猾
That was pretty smart,
精心的布置犯罪现场
Staging the crime scene like the stalker video,
看起来像是别人干的
Making it look like someone else did it.
她把你当父亲一样尊敬你
She loved you like a father.
她仰慕你的那种眼神
The way she looked up to you...
让我更加迷恋你
It made me love you more.
看着我
Look at me.
我想请个律师
I'd like a lawyer now.
布雷知道了她丈夫
Bree turned on her husband
对海利做了什么之后哭个不停
The moment she found out what he had done to Hayley.
而且勿庸置疑  她提出了离婚
Needless to say, she's filed for divorce.
难怪海利不跟布雷说一声就逃走了
No wonder Hayley couldn't tell Bree why she ran away.
她找不到合适的对象
You see, she didn't have anyone to talk to.
所以她只能做一件事  写出来
So she did the one thing that she could. She wrote about it.
这让我想起  我写那本
That kinda reminds me of when I wrote
《屠杀将至》时的心情
"When it comes to slaughter."
我一直想要
It was at a time in my life when I was just
一种想要搞清楚  不重要了
I was trying to work through... it's not important.
所以他认罪了
So is he pleading out?
肯定的  帕尔马特在他外衣里
Oh, he can try. Perlmutter ran his coat and found
发现了和海利身上相同的火药残留
The same gun powder residue that found in Hayley.
估计要坐一段牢了
He is going away for a long time.
很好
Good.
干得漂亮  你们俩都是
Nice job. Both of you.
你准备怎么跟阿丽克西斯说
So what are you gonna tell Alexis?
像以往一样
What I always tell her,
实话实说
The truth.
海利·玛利亚·布鲁  我们爱你想你
Hayley Maria Blue, we love and miss you.
这首歌献给你
The song's for you.